Randall House mss., 1975-1988. LMC 2722
Lilly Library
Randall House mss.
1975-2013
Lilly Library
Randall House Publications (Firm)
LMC 2722
28 Boxes
The Randall House mss., 1975-2013, consists of the business records and correspondence of the San Francisco bookselling firm Randall and Windle and of its successor Randall House.
Access Restrictions
This collection is open for research.
Many collections are housed offsite; retrieval requires advance notice. Please make an appointment a minimum of one week in advance of your visit.
Administrative History
Randall House Rare Books is a bookselling firm in Santa Barbara, CA, run by Ron Randall and Pia Oliver since 1980. The company grew out of the San Francisco firm Randall and Windle, opened in 1975 by Ron Randall and John Windle.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into the following series: I. Paid Bills; II. Miscellaneous; III. Appraisals; IV. Books for Sale; V. Book Descriptions; VI. Inventories.
Scope and Content Note
The Randall House mss., 1975-2013, consist of the business records and correspondence of the San Francisco bookselling firm Randall and Windle, and of its successor Randall House. Included are ledger sheets, paid bills, payroll records, correspondence, and tax records and receipts.
Acquisition Information
Acquired: 1980s-2015
Booksellers and bookselling; publishing; Correspondence; Letters; Account books; Randall and Windle (Firm); Randall House Publications (Firm)
- I. Paid Bills
  - 2011, 71 folders (Box 1)
  - 2009, 40 folders (Box 10)
  - Paid Bills A-Z, 2012 (Box 23)
  - Bills - Alphabetical, 2012 (Box 23)
  - Paid Bills A-Z, 2013 (Box 24)
  - Paid Bills A-Z, 2008 (Box 25)
  - Paid Bills A-H, 2006 (Box 25)
  - Paid Bills I-Z, 2006 (Box 26)
  - Bills - Chronological, 2012 (Box 26)
  - ABAA Membership Directories, 1981-2013 (Box 26)
- II. Miscellaneous
  - Miscellaneous, 9 folders (Box 2)
  - Correspondence A-Q, 2002-2008 (Box 27)
  - Correspondence R-Z, 2002-2008 (Box 28)
- III. Appraisals
  - 18 folders (Box 2)
  - 26 folders (Box 6)
  - 67 folders (Box 7)
  - 24 folders (Box 9)
- IV. Books for Sale
  - 30 folders (Box 12)
- V. Book Descriptions
  - 68 folders (Box 3)
  - 24 folders (Box 4)
- VI. Inventories
  - Alphabetical and Chronological, 2011; 2 boxed bindings (Box 8)
  - Chronological, 2003; 2 boxed bindings (Box 13)
  - Alphabetical, 2004; 2 boxed bindings (Box 14)
  - Chronological, 2004; 2 boxed bindings (Box 15)
  - Alphabetical, 2003; 2 boxed bindings (Box 16)
  - Alphabetical and Chronological, 2005; 2 boxed bindings (Box 17)
  - Alphabetical and Chronological, 2006; 2 boxed bindings (Box 18)
  - Alphabetical and Chronological, 2007; 2 boxed bindings (Box 19)
  - Alphabetical and Chronological, 2008; 2 boxed bindings (Box 20)
  - Alphabetical and Chronological, 2009; 2 boxed bindings (Box 21)
  - Alphabetical and Chronological, 2010; 2 boxed bindings (Box 22)